Hello friends, my name is Sachin and today
I am back with a video, you can click here.
Friends, today we are going to talk
about Manipal Sinha's Pro Health Plus plan. Friends, in the last video
I told you that this plan
comes in different variants. In this,
we
will review all the plans one by one. In the last video, I
reviewed the product plan. If
you want to watch that video, I will
give you its link in the description here or I will also give you the link here on the i button
so that you
can click and watch the previous video and understand
how its product plan works.
Friends, in the same way, we will cover other plans in the future as well.
In this video, we will review the Plus plan. So
friends, let's start the
review of the Plus plan. Friends, first of all, let
me tell you that the maximum number of
options available in it is 4.5 lakhs
and in this way,
you can increase this plan up to 50 lakhs.
These are such expenses when you were
not admitted to the hospital and before that, you had consulted a
doctor.  I had agreed on the fees,
bought some medicines, got some medical checkups done,
so please bear all those expenses.
For which you will get 60
days time here and similarly when
you are discharged and go back home, then
we call it post-hospitalization expenses
which are of 180 days here, meaning even
after you have been discharged,
if you have consulted a doctor or you have
paid some fees or taken medicines or got some
medical checkups done, then all the
expenses incurred for 180 days related to the same disease will be given to
you as
reimbursement here. Talking about the room rent
limit, friends, I found this to be a very
good feature here that now you can
take a room of any category here,
even in a simple plan of Rs 4 or 5.5 lakh, but
you cannot book a room of suite or above category here,
you can take a room of any category below that,
friends, so these are such treatments
where you do not need 24-hour respiration,
friends, in this you are admitted in the morning
and in the evening you are discharged and go
home.  Mostly these are surgeries only. There are
540 procedures of this type here, for which you pay the money and
get cashless treatment,
and the complete list of this is friends,
which you can read by going to the policy words,
I will give you the link of it
in the description, from there you can download and
read it. Talking about community bonus,
friends, we also call it no claim bonus,
here it is 10% guaranteed, which
means it does not matter whether your claim comes or not, suppose
you had
taken this policy for ₹10 lakh, then
you will get 10% guaranteed here
whether your claim came or not,
along with this, friends, it goes up to 200 percent, that is, it can
double your submission
if you continue this plan with the company.
Talking about restore benefit, friends,
you will get it here for unlimited time,
but keep in mind that this is
not available for meeting from time to time.
Suppose someone had kidney disease and
again your submission is completely over
and you want that we should get the restoration of all this for
kidney disease again and
we should get the claim for that too here, so
friends, it is not like that, if suppose there is
any heart disease or any
accidental claim, then the
claims for all the diseases will be given to you
here under restoration for an unlimited
time,
talking about income tax benefit, friends, here
you get this benefit under section 80d, let's
talk about domicile treatment,
friends, that is also available here,
friends, what happens under this is that suppose there is no
room available in any hospital in your city, the condition of the patient is
not such that he can be admitted in the hospital,
but you are
giving them treatment at home, doctors are also coming there,
nurses are also visiting and
there
you are giving them treatment almost like a hospital.  If you are giving this, then
friends, this will be
considered under domicile treatment, its duration should be
more than a minimum of 3 days,
if this is the case then you will be given
its reimbursement
in the domestic section, which
is covered up to the same limit. Talking about the entry limit,
friends, here you
can take this plan from 18 years onwards, this
entry is ahead and there is
no maximum entry ahead in this, friends, if a
person here is 60 years old, 70 years old, 80 years old,
then he can also opt for this plan.
Talking about newborn baby,
friends, you can cover newborn baby here in 91 days
and
similarly, the limit for dependent child is
23 years,
if for example, a dependent becomes 24 years old, then for that
you will have to take a separate policy here. Talking about policy duration
discount, friends, 7.5%
for 2 years and  If you take this plan for 3 years, you will get a 10%
discount here. Let's also talk about health checkups,
friends, this is also a very good thing
here that you get a health checkup almost every year. There are
some prilisted tests,
if you ask me which tests are there,
I will tell you or it is
also written in the policy words, so you
can go there and read it.
You will not get it in the first year. When you get the next
renewal done, you will keep getting it regularly from that day
till every year,
friends. So here, there is a hospital cover of up to ₹1000,
that means you can get
ambulance cover from the company multiple times by paying Rs. 3,000 each time.
Talking about worldwide emergency cover, friends, this is also a very good
benefit of this. If you face
any such emergency that you have to
go outside India for
treatment, then
you can do that too for a certain time. This
is built within the plan itself.  You will
not have to pay extra for this. Let's move ahead
friends, let's talk about organ donor
cover, so friends, this is also
covered here. Suppose during a treatment,
sometimes you have to take an organ from someone as a donation,
like a liver
transplant or a kidney transplant, then
friends, the
donor here will have a surgery and
his medical expenses, so those
expenses will also be covered in this plan,
which you can avail the benefit till the end.
Friends, there is a state-of-the-art treatment,
like Ayurveda, Unani, Siddha,
Homeopathy,
if you are given any such treatment during the treatment, then that
too will be
covered for you here, but it is
very important to have 24-hour respiration in it,
you should keep this in mind.
Talking about health maintenance benefit, friends,
which we call OPD cover in your language, there is
also OPD cover here, which you will get ₹2000
every year, if suppose you have
consulted a doctor outside, or for any medical  If you have got a
checkup done, then you can get it done up to ₹2000
under this policy. Friends,
here you will get an option of Expert
Opinion on Critical Analysis. Suppose
you get a serious illness, whoever has
taken the policy faces a serious problem
and they want to take an opinion from the
doctors on the panel of Manipal Singhania,
want to do consultation, then you
can also do that under this.
Friends, there is a Healthy
Rewards Program here, if you
follow their parameters and
here you can avail a discount of up to 5% on renewal
in individual policy and up to 20%
on family doctor.
For this also, I would say that you should
read the browser or policy words, then
you will understand well
how it works. Friends, here there is
zone based pricing, meaning here the
whole of India is divided into 300 zones,
like Mumbai, Thane, Navi.
Mumbai, Gujarat, Delhi NCR comes in Zone 2,
friends, Bengaluru, Hyderabad,
Chennai, Chandigarh, Ludhiana, Kolkata and Pune do
not come, they come in Zone 3, so friends, the
premium of Zone Van will be a little
higher, that of Zone 2 will be less and that
of Zone 3 will be even less, that is why friends, the
treatment expenses here are quite low, that is
why their premium has also been
divided here in a proper manner, but
friends, if anyone from Zone 2 goes to Zone Van for
treatment, then he will have to pay a copay of 10% here, that
means he will have to pay
10% of the bill from his pocket, similarly, if
someone from Zone 3 goes to Zone 2 for
treatment, then he will have to pay 10% there too, if
someone from Zone 3 goes to Zone Van for
treatment, then he will have to
pay up to 20% there, friends, let's
talk about optional cover here, for this
you will have to pay some extra money,
like the first option is
Hospital Delhi Cash Benefit, friends, if
you have a hospital, then you
also suffer some loss of business, so if you  If you have
taken this option then you will get ₹2000 for a
maximum of 30 days.
Suppose if there is a host plantation for 5 days
and you have taken this ₹2000 plan off
then you will get a maximum of ₹10000 here. In the
same way, friends,
you can avail the benefit of this plan for 30 days.
Talking about the digital option, friends, many
people say that I like this plan
but I already have a policy of a company,
so I
want to take this plan in such a super top, then
you can take that also.
Suppose you have an old policy of ₹500000
or an old policy of 10 lakhs
and you want to take a sub-inspection of 50 lakhs here,
then you can take that also here.
As soon as your debit amount
crosses from here, this policy will start
giving you benefits.
You want to make it a base policy
like a normal policy.  If I
want to do it in the same way, then
you can definitely do that, but this will be possible only at the
time of renewal.
Friends, there is an option in this. Some people
feel that the premium is too high
and I want it to be reduced.
If any bill comes, then I can
also share 10 to 20% of the amount.
So friends, there is a voluntary
opt-out in this. You can take this option
and accordingly your premium will be
reduced. Friends, there is an option called
waiver of mandatory co-payment. Friends,
in this plan, whenever your future or the future of the
insured turns 65 years or
more, then you have to bear 20% of the bill
from your pocket. If, suppose
you do not want to bear it,
I want the entire bill to be paid by the company,
then you
can take the option of mandatory co-payment here. With this, your entire bill will be paid. There will be
no 20% charge here.
Friends, there is one thing here called community
bonus booster. This means that here
you will get one thing which I told you last time.
In this you get a bonus of 10% but
if you take this option then
instead of 10% you will get a bonus of 25%
and it is guaranteed that yours will be increased to a maximum of
200%.
Friends, now let's talk about the base covers.
Friends, the first add-on cover here is
critical analysis. Suppose you
opt for this critical and
whatever time you have taken, suppose you have taken a
subashod of 10 lakhs and you have
also opted for this benefit, then friends, what will happen is that
you will get 10 lakh rupees for treatment and
along with that the company will reimburse you 10 lakh
rupees and you will reimburse it to me
because you
need a list of all the listed critical diseases of the company, friends, you
can ask for it from me or it will be
mentioned in the policy words or inside the browser also that if
you are diagnosed with any of the listed diseases, then
on diagnosis itself the
company will give you that additional lumpsum benefit
in your bank account.  If the numbers are given, let's move
ahead and talk
about a Health 360 plan. Friends,
this is also an add-on cover, which we
also call a rider. So, what happens here is that
many things like your P
kit, your hand gloves,
section charge, TP fee,
alcohol swipe, the money for these things is
not covered. If you have taken this rider, then
friends, the money for these things will also be
covered, which we call non-medical
items. Along with this, you are given the
method to buy durable medical equipment up to ₹1 lakh, like here the
doctor told you to buy a bi-pack machine,
you have to buy a wheelchair, so
friends,
no insurance company pays for such items,
but if you have taken this rider, then
you will be given up to ₹1 lakh for it. So, there is
a rider here called 360 Advance,
under which you can take any room category,
like
suite or above category
is not available in this plan.  If you have added this add-on, then
you will get it. Along with this, you were
not reducing the coverage for restoration here, so by taking this,
your coverage will also be increased from impression to
illness. Along with this,
friends, air ambulance will also be added in it, in
which the maximum limit will be 10 lakh
rupees. Friends, the
cost of treatment will be covered because
you have bought this add-on cover. This will be an
addition, that is, it will be extra.
Friends, these three riders are
also an OPD. I will
make a separate detailed video for these because very
soon I will bring it to you, in which
I will explain to you in detail about these three riders,
how to reduce them. So
here the third rider is 360 OPD, which is
inside it, this is the right of OPD. Here, for example, suppose
you take doctor consultation, do
some medical checkup or
you buy pharmacy or you mean
buy medicines, then here
you will get all the money for that.
This OPD plan is on cashless
basis, friends.  You will get cashless cover
and in this, whatever time you take in
OPD, 20% of that medicine
cost is given to you here. Friends, let's talk about
premium calculation. If you want to
calculate the premium of this plan
and with advance, then I will
give you the link in the description from where
you can calculate your premium and if you
want, you can also buy the policy. If you
want me to give you the link
on WhatsApp, then you
can ask for this link on WhatsApp also.
Friends, there is also a mother benefit in this plan,
so we will discuss that here too.
First of all, let's talk about the
expenses, here you will be given up to ₹15,000 for
normal delivery and
₹25,000 will be given for C-section, that is,
if your
delivery takes place through cesarean section, then you will be given
₹25,000 in that and this maximum is
reduced to two deliveries. If it is the third or
fourth delivery, then you will not be given this claim.  The
waiting period here is
48 months, that is, only after four years,
friends, you will be able to avail the benefit of this option.
Friends, let's talk about newborn baby
expenses, friends, this will also be
covered by the de-vain here. If
you have taken any maternity benefit
and any baby is born here, then
if the baby is in the first position, then that
too is covered here, but friends, this will
come under maternity expenses only. As
I told you that in normal delivery, the maximum is
15,000 and in C-section, the maximum is
25,000, so it will come within this limit.
Friends, if the baby is vaccinated here, then the
first year's vaccination will be
given by the company here and its
limit will be above the metro. And
friends, here you will be given the benefits according to our national immunization program.
If you want or not, we want to get
some extra vaccines,
want to give some extra vaccinations to the child, then you will not be able to do that
friends, which the government has approved here.
You will be
reimbursed for the same according to the completed program. Friends, here
I told you that there is a four-year waiting
period, but you can also reduce it.
This is an optional cover, for which
you will have to pay a little extra money,
which you will be able to reduce from 48 months to
24 months.
Meaning, the earlier waiting period of four years will
now be reduced to two years, meaning you will be able to
avail the benefits in this matter even after just two years.
Friends, I am also very active on social media.
If you want to connect with me,
you can search for me on Facebook as
Insurance Sachin,
you can follow me there.
You can also follow me on Instagram. If
you have any questions regarding this plan,
you can WhatsApp me.
You can also tweet to me on Twitter as
Insurance Sachin.
Here is my Telegram
link, you can also join me here. You can get information about
insurance here.  You'll keep getting new
updates. If you have any
questions, you can also write me an email.
I'll definitely answer all your questions.
Friends, let's talk about the
major exclusions, meaning under
what conditions you don't get a claim under this plan.
Friends, first of all, let's
talk about free existing
diseases. If you already have a disease and the
company has issued a policy for that disease,
meaning you declared that disease, then there will be a
waiting period of 4 years. Friends,
you will be able to get cover for that disease only after 4 years. Friends, the waiting period here is of 2 years. For example, there are
some diseases like cataract, hernia,
joint replacement, kidney stone, cold
blood surgeries. Friends, these are such diseases that
every company provides cover for them only after approximately 2
years. So here
too, it is of two years because there is a normal
waiting period of 30 days. Friends,
you will not get any money for any treatment here.
You will only get accidental cover if the
accident occurs within 30 days.  Yours
and apart from that, no other disease is covered here.
Friends, it will be
covered here if you turn 65
or above. But I
told you that if you
take the copayment option here, then
that will also be removed from here. So your plan will
reduce it like a normal plan.
Friends, there is a 90-day waiting period for
critical illness here. I told you that you
can take add-on cover for critical illness.
If any of the listed critical illnesses is
diagnosed in it, then you will get cover for it only if it happens after 90 days.
If it is diagnosed before that, then
you will not get cover for it. Friends, I told
you that the waiting period for maternity here
is 48 months, but you can reduce it to 24 months.
Friends, if you want to
read it in more details, then I will give you its policy
words and browser link
in the description. You can go to its
expanded terms and conditions and
read everything there.  So friends, I hope
you have understood this plan.
If you still have any questions,
you can ask me in the comments.
Share this video with your friends.
If you liked this plan and you
want me to keep bringing more such videos for you, then
tell me on
which topics you want to see videos.
My name is Sachin Verma. I will meet
you in the next video.
Thank you very much for watching this video.